Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 2 Month(s)

Notice Period: 15 Days or less

[Electronics/Telecommunication]

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E.

SANTHOSH KUMAR A.L (1) Featured

UI Developer seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, UI Development, Web Development, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, JavaScript, Bootstrap, React. Js, ¡Query, HTML, CSS



Current Designation: UI Developer

Current Company: Kloud9 technologies - Phoenix Human

Capital Pvt Ltd

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: UI/Software Developer, Software Engineering, Software Development, UI Development, Web

Development, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement

Gathering, JavaScript, Bootstrap, React. Js, jQuery, HTML, CSS

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Summary

B.E degree holder in Electronics and Communication Engineering with 3.2+ years of experience in UI/Web Development, seeks a position to utilize my technical skills and abilities in a fair way and looking forword to take opportunity in the industry and to be one step ahead.

Identify usability and develop functional and smooth, easy-to-operate web applications

Development experience in JavaScript,HTML5,CSS,Reactis,Redux,Bootstrap.

2.0 year of experience in working in WebDevelopment

Experience in using React JS components, Forms, Events, Keys, Router.

Knowledge on Responsive Web Design.

Perform website maintenance and enhancements.

Monitored technical aspects of the front-end delivery for projects.

Work Experience

Kloud9 technologies - Phoenix Human Capital Pvt Ltd as UI Developer

Feb 2020 to Till Date

Involved in development of user experience interface UI strategy, UI requirements

Developed component based architecture using ReactJS.

Developed a flexible and well-structured front-end code.

Working closely with Backend Developers and Testing Team to produce User-friendly dynamic web applications.

Innovellent Technology Pvt Ltd as UI Developer

Sep 2018 to Jan 2020

Project Title: Job Portal Design and Development.

Workforce Development Agency (WDA) has a clear mission to lead, drive and champion workforce development, enhancing the employability and competitiveness of Singapore's workforce. To meet those requirements, WDA has come up with initiative of developing three different portals for Employees, Employers and Training Providers.

Involved in development of user experience interface UI strategy, UI requirements

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=7d9fd3d6c1fb95b3290d147d3e5a6eb751085d074a175f105045120a0c...

Developed component based architecture using ReactJS.

Developed a flexible and well-structured front-end architecture, along with the RESTAPIs to Support it.

Working closely with Backend Developers and Testing Team to produce User-friendly dynamic web applications.

Project Title: Plotmonitor System.

Plot monitor provide services to monitor Plot/Sites and provide apartments related services including, Property Tax, payments and other value added services. Plot Monitoring by Plot Monitor is backend by team of trained field executives. Plot Monitor Provides its user technology-enabled services to enhance the overall customer experience.

Role: UI developer

Environments: Bootstrap4, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Ajax, Laravel.

Responsibility:

Developed a flexible and well-structured front-end architecture. Involved in development of user experience interface UI strategy. Handled UI with JavaScript.

Defect fixing, and Checking all UI.

Fixing Cross browser compatibility issues and performance improvements.

Intersog Automation Software Pvt Ltd as UI Developer

Jul 2017 to Aug 2018

Project Title: Apartment Booking system.

Apartment Management System made our Society's Maintenance related activities more Systematic and Easy to handle. Apartment Management System is helping societies to convert from paper based societies to an e-Society. With tools like Security, Facility, Assets, Events, Building Management, User Management Parking area available at finger tips of the Managing Committee, the society is managed professionally and items resolved in a timely manner.

Involved in development of user experience interface UI strategy.

Handled UI with javascript.

Defect fixing, and Checking all UI.

Fixing Cross browser compatibility issues and performance improvements.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Visveswaraiah Technological University (VTU) in 2016

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap			
React Js, Jquery			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Kannada				

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time